Mehmet Fatih YAR

Kayseri, Turkey



fyar87@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/mehmetfatihyar

Summary

I ended my educational adventure by leaving my graduate program at Yıldız Technical University at the thesis stage and started my professional business life in the private sector. For a while, I gained experience in the private sector in the field of urban design and planning and continued in the public sector. During this period, after getting my SPK Real Estate Appraisal License, I established MFY Real Estate Appraisal company. I have been serving in the field of real estate appraisal for about 5 years.

Now I am starting the bootcamp, which will bring a new breath to my business life in order to catch up with the era. By completing the course, I aim to step into a brand new business life as a data scientist.

Eğitim serüvenini Yıldız Teknik Üniversitesinde lisansüstü programımı tez aşamasında bırakarak sonlandırdım ve profesyonel iş hayatına özel sektörde başladım. Bir süre kentsel tasarım ve planlama alanında özel sektörde tecrübe edinerek kamu alanında devam ettim. Bu süre zarfı içerisinde de Spk Gayrimenkul Değerleme Lisansımı aldıktan sonra MFY Gayrimenkul Değerleme şirketini kurdum. Yaklaşık 5 yıldır gayrimenkul değerleme alanında hizmet vermekteyim.

Şimdi çağı yakalamak adına iş hayatıma yeni bir soluk getirecek bootcamp e başlıyorum. Kursu tamamlayarak data scientist olarak yepyeni bir iş hayatına adım atmayı hedefliyorum.

Experience



Information Technology Student

Clarusway

Sep 2021 - Present (2 months +) Full Stack Development, AWS, DevOps, Data Science

Gayrimenkul Değerleme Uzmanı/Real Estate Appraiser

MFY Gayrimenkul Değerleme/MFY Real Estate Appraisal Oct 2016 - Present (5 years 1 month +)

Gayrimenkul Değerleme Uzmanı

Mezopotamya Kentsel Yenileme Merkezi Sep 2021 - Present (2 months +)

Real Estate Appraiser

Denge Gayrimenkul Değerleme ve Danışmanlık A.Ş Jun 2021 - Present (5 months +) Solution partner with contract Real estate appraiser

Real Estate Appraiser

Makro Gayrimenkul Değerleme A.Ş.

Feb 2017 - Present (4 years 9 months +) Solution partner with contract Real estate appraiser

Real Estate Appraiser

Zirve Gayrimenkul Değerleme
Oct 2016 - Present (5 years 1 month +)
Solution partner with contract
Real estate appraiser

Kentsel Tasarım Uzmanı

Aksaray Belediyesi Jun 2014 - Aug 2016 (2 years 3 months)

SALARHA ŞEHİRCİLİK

SALARHA ŞEHİRCİLİK MİM. MÜH. İNŞ. SAN. VE TİC. LTD. ŞTİ. Feb 2012 - May 2014 (2 years 4 months)

📘 Atelye70 Planlama ve Kentsel Tasarım Grubu

Atelye70 Planners&Architects Sep 2011 - Feb 2012 (6 months)

free lancer

integral architecture&urban design Oct 2010 - Nov 2010 (2 months)

Education

Yildiz Technical University

Master of Architecture - MArch, Urban Spatial Organization and Design - City/Urban, and Regional Planning 2011 - 2014

Yildiz Technical University

BA, City/Urban, Community and Regional Planning 2005 - 2011

Licenses & Certifications

Licensed Real Estate Appraiser - Capital Markets Board of Turkey 406744

Urban Planner/ Group F - Çevre ve Şehircilik Bakanlığı 335/347

Skills

Real Estate Appraisal • Urban Planning • AutoCAD • Urban Design • Planning • Design Research • Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) • Graphic Design • Python (Programming Language) • Linux

Honors & Awards



Uşak National Bus Terminal Complex Urban Design and Architectural Project **Competition 1th Mention**

Jan 2012 1th Mention award